<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>archlinux on misctechmusings.com</title><link>https://p0rkjello.github.io/tags/archlinux/</link><description>Recent content in archlinux on misctechmusings.com</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en</language><atom:link href="https://p0rkjello.github.io/tags/archlinux/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Archlinux Kernel Repair</title><link>https://p0rkjello.github.io/archlinux-kernel-repair/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://p0rkjello.github.io/archlinux-kernel-repair/</guid><description>
{%- include toc.html -%}
So I managed to uninstall my kernel In an effort to get VMware Workstation running I needed to downgrade my kernel. I installed the new kernel and got everything setup. Sometime later the system reverted to the newer version.
I already had the package exclusion IgnorePjg = linux, linux-headers in pacman.conf. So I decided to purge the newer kernel 3.16 from the system. After doing so, I reinstalled the downlevel kernel 3.</description></item><item><title>Archlinux Powerpill Setup</title><link>https://p0rkjello.github.io/archlinux-powerpill-setup/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://p0rkjello.github.io/archlinux-powerpill-setup/</guid><description>
Arch Linux Powerpill Setup Powerpill is a wrapper for Archlinux package management tool, pacman. This is a short tutorial on setting up powerpill for concurrent downloads without using the reflector.
Powerpill is a wrapper script written by Xyne for pacman that speeds up package retrieval by using aria2c for concurrent/segmented downloads. It determines the target packages of requested synchronization operation and then uses the mirrorlist to create a comprehensive metalink. This metalink is then piped to the download manager aria2 for package retrieval.</description></item><item><title>Powerline on Archlinux</title><link>https://p0rkjello.github.io/powerline-on-archlinux/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://p0rkjello.github.io/powerline-on-archlinux/</guid><description>
Powerline on Archlinux I recently switched from GNU Screen to Tmux. While reviewing random tmux.confs on Github I stumbled onto the screenshot below of tmux &amp;amp; powerline.
Powerline is a statusline plugin for vim, and provides statuslines and prompts for several other applications, including zsh, bash, tmux, IPython, Awesome and Qtile.
https://github.com/gpakosz/.tmux
An AUR package available for Powerline. However for this document I am going to detail the standard installation.</description></item></channel></rss>