<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>gnome on misctechmusings.com</title>
    
    
    
    <link>/tags/gnome/</link>
    <description>Recent content in gnome on misctechmusings.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/gnome/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Persistent Gnome shell in Lucid</title>
      <link>/persistent-gnome-shell-in-lucid/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/persistent-gnome-shell-in-lucid/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          GNOME Shell is the defining technology of the GNOME 3 desktop user experience. It provides core interface functions like switching to windows and launching applications. GNOME Shell takes advantage of the capabilities of modern graphics hardware and introduces innovative user interface concepts to provide a delightful and easy to use experience.
Availability and Status
The GNOME Shell is currently in active development and while many planned features are not yet implemented it is stable enough for everyday use.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solarized colors on Gnome terminal</title>
      <link>/solarized-colors-on-gnome-terminal/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/solarized-colors-on-gnome-terminal/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          Solarized is a beautiful color palette. The palette was designed for readability and comes with both light and dark options.
 Solarized is a sixteen color palette (eight monotones, eight accent colors) designed for use with terminal and gui applications. It has several unique properties. I designed this color scheme with both precise CIELAB lightness relationships and a refined set of hues based on fixed color wheel relationships. It has been tested extensively in real world use on color calibrated displays (as well as uncalibrated/intentionally miscalibrated displays) and in a variety of lighting conditions.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Warning failed to load theme</title>
      <link>/warning-failed-to-load-theme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/warning-failed-to-load-theme/</guid>
      <description>
        
          
          
          
        
        
        
          While recklessly installing/testing some new themes I broke my GUI. Nothing seemed to be working right. After rebooting the box I was sitting at a blank screen. A quick check of ps -aux showed Gnome and Xorg running. What gives?
Fired up journalctl and saw a bunch of these listed. Yep that looks like a place I might have screwed up.
gnome-session[7460]: Window manager warning: Failed to load theme &amp;quot;Adwaita&amp;quot;: Failed to find a valid file for theme Adwaita gnome-session[7460]: Window manager warning: Failed to load theme &amp;quot;Simple&amp;quot;: Failed to find a valid file for theme Simple gnome-session[7460]: Window manager warning: Failed to load theme &amp;quot;ThinIce&amp;quot;: Failed to find a valid file for theme ThinIce gnome-session[7460]: Window manager warning: Failed to load theme &amp;quot;Zukitre&amp;quot;: Failed to find a valid file for theme Zukitre gnome-session[7460]: Window manager warning: Failed to load theme &amp;quot;Default&amp;quot;: Failed to find a valid file for theme Default gnome-session[7460]: Window manager warning: Failed to load theme &amp;quot;Emacs&amp;quot;: Failed to find a valid file for theme Emacs gnome-session[7460]: Window manager warning: Failed to load theme &amp;quot;Redmond&amp;quot;: Failed to find a valid file for theme Redmond gnome-session[7460]: Window manager warning: Failed to load theme &amp;quot;Moka&amp;quot;: Failed to find a valid file for theme Moka gnome-session[7460]: Window manager warning: Failed to load theme &amp;quot;Numix&amp;quot;: Failed to find a valid file for theme Numix gnome-session[7460]: Window manager warning: Failed to load theme &amp;quot;Zukitwo&amp;quot;: Failed to find a valid file for theme Zukitwo I quick Google search found a recommendation to reinstall the gnome-themes-standard package.
          
        
        </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>